### **Dhriti Pandhi**

419-297-7957 | dhriti.pandhi@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/dhritipandhi

#### **SUMMARY**

Attorney with 3+ years of experience in corporate and securities law, and 3+ years of experience in trade law and international intellectual property policy. Background includes work with two AmLaw 200 firms and the U.S. Government. Admitted to practice law in California, the District of Columbia, the Supreme Court of the United States and the United States Court of International Trade. Seeking transactional legal role in the entertainment industry.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **BAKER & MCKENZIE LLP** | Washington, DC Associate Attorney, Corporate & Securities

March 2016 - August 2019

- Assisted in negotiation of \$100 million sale of academic publishing company client's life sciences division;
  drafted disclosure schedule to the share purchase agreement by coordinating with various legal teams
- Monitored and researched SEC rule updates and relevant news in '33 and '34 Act reporting to ensure ongoing compliance for various clients
- Drafted, revised, and edited a multitude of periodic reports including 10-Ks, 10-Qs, 8-Ks, Proxy Statements, as well as Section 16 filings; reviewed client's prospectus supplements in Preferred Stock and bond offerings
- Led due diligence work stream and communication with counsel across a dozen global offices for Fortune 500 fast food client company's cross-border restructuring
- Selected as in-house attorney detail to European grocer client's new U.S. headquarters; streamlined corporate governance processes and communication between legal and other departments
- Advised biosciences client in venture capital transaction for early stage medical therapy technology, including reviewing licensing agreements of medical therapy to prospective partners
- Baker McKenzie's Pro Bono Award; Diversity & Inclusion Committee; Summer Associate Mentor

# **U.S. FEDERAL GOVERNMENT** | Washington, DC **Presidential Management Fellow (PMF)**

**December 2012 - March 2016** 

- Held positions in highly selective PMF program as an Intellectual Property Policy Trade Specialist within the International Trade Administration at the U.S. Department of Commerce; an Attorney in the Office of the United States Trade Representative (USTR) within the Executive Office of the President; and a Policy Analyst in the Wage and Hour Division at the U.S. Department of Labor
- Regularly liaised with entertainment industry, including the Motion Picture Association of America, The Walt Disney Company, the Recording Industry Association of America, and the Entertainment Software Association
- Lead representative at the WTO's TRIPS Council meetings, the UN's WIPO Lisbon Act negotiations in Geneva, the U.S.-Taiwan Trade and Investment Framework Agreement and the U.S.-China Joint Commission on Commerce and Trade in Beijing to abate industry issues in international markets during various negotiations
- One of three attorneys to litigate the United States' case of first impression arising under the labor chapter of the Dominican Republic-Central America-United States Free Trade Agreement
- Co-author to the legal brief comprising the United States' submission to the dispute settlement arbitral panel
- Entrusted by the General Counsel of USTR with developing evidence in both English and Spanish including taking dozens of depositions in Guatemala City at various labor unions
- Counseled U.S. Department of Labor's Wage and Hour Division on efficacy of strategic enforcement tools such as liquidated damages, enhanced settlement agreements, and civil money penalties

### **DINSMORE & SHOHL LLP** | Cincinnati, OH **Summer Associate**

July 2010 - August 2010; May 2011 - August 2011

- Authored memoranda analyzing digital studio client's classification under California's Talent Agencies Act
- Advised businesses seeking to invest and expand operations in the British Virgin Islands on foreign tax law, and researched and drafted legal memoranda on product liability law, employment law and insurance law

### U.S. DISTRICT COURT for the DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA | Washington, DC

May 2010 - July 2010

Law Clerk for the Honorable Senior Judge Gladys Kessler

- Drafted potential rebuttals and defenses to petitioners' arguments in a Guantanamo detainee case considering Constitutional law and international law arguments
- Authored draft legal opinion on the Constitutional issue of standing in an environmental law case

### **SELF-EMPLOYED WOMEN'S ASSOCIATION (SEWA)** | Ahmedabad, India **Research Associate**

September 2007 - March 2008

- Youngest associate to lead research team to assess the state of literacy for poverty-stricken women in Ahmedabad through 100 interviews and secondary research
- Co-authored report with founder Ela Bhatt on SEWA's ability to assist marginalized women throughout its 35year history
- Participated in the Indian Trade Expo represented by SEWA members employed in the textile industry to research the impact of access to international trade markets

#### **EDUCATION**

JURIS DOCTOR | Boston College Law School | Newton, MA | 2012

Grimes Moot Court Competition; Law Student Association Alumni Committee Chair; South Asian Law Student Association Secretary; Sole PMF in Class of 2012; Pro Bono Achievement Award; Boston College Law School Civil Litigation Clinic Student Attorney

MASTER OF PHILOSOPHY (MPhil) | University of Cambridge | Cambridge, UK | 2009

High Pass; Researched international mechanisms, trade agreements, trade barriers and historical market access points for developing countries through coursework in Development Economics; Rotary Ambassadorial Scholarship; Cambridge Overseas Trust Scholarship; Graduate Student Committee Welfare Officer

BS ECONOMICS (DISTINCTION) / BSBA FINANCE (HONORS) / BA SPANISH (HONORS) | The Ohio State University | Columbus, OH | 2007

Magna cum laude; Honors Senior Thesis in Economics; Outstanding Female Senior in Fisher College of Business; Outstanding Graduating Senior in College of Arts and Sciences; President of the National Society of Collegiate Scholars; Mortar Board and Phi Beta Kappa; Studied abroad in Spain, Uganda, and the United Kingdom

#### **LANGUAGES**

Highly proficient in Spanish, Gujarati and Kutchi (Indian dialect)